A Guide to the Warren County (Va.) Lists of Voters Registered, 1836-1953
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Warren County (Va.) Lists of Voters Registered, 1836-1953
The Library of Virginia
1013639-1096720 circa
1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes) and 120 v.
Warren County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court papers from Warren County.
Historical Information
Warren County was named for Joseph Warren, the revolutionary patriot who sent Paul Revere and William Dawes on their famous rides and who was killed at the Battle of Bunker Hill. The county was formed from Frederick and Shenandoah counties in 1836.
The 1902 voter registration books were created following the passage of the 1902 Virginia state constitution. The purpose of the 1902 state constitution was to maintain white suffrage while eliminating African-American voters by means of literacy tests as well as property and poll tax requirements.
The Nineteenth Amendment was granted the right to vote to women. It was proposed on June 4, 1919 and ratified on August 18, 1920.
Scope and Content
Warren County (Va.) Lists of Voters Registered, 1836-1953, includes three boxes of commissions, polls, affidavits and reports for the period 1836-1854 and 1861-1941. There are list of voters in the books Permanent Poll of Voters, 1902-1903 and Voter Registration Book, Colored, 1905-1908. There are thirty five list of Colored Voters for the years 1892-1953. There are and eighty three List of White Voters for the years 1884-1952 and four undated list. The Lists of Voters are from the Precincts of Bentonville; Bowman; Browntown; Cedarville; Fork Union; Front Royal; Front Royal, North; Front Royal, South; Keller's School; Leary's School; Linden; Milldale; Reliance; Riverton; Rockland; and Waterlick. These precincts were in the Magisterial Districts of Cedarville, Fork, Front Royal, and South River.
Warren County lists of registered voters consist of the individual rolls of registered voters both colored and white. Rolls also include names of women who registered following passage of Nineteenth Amendment in 1920. Information found in the rolls includes date of registration; number of registered voter; name of registered voter; date of birth; age; occupation; residence; length of residence in state, county, and precinct; whether exempt from poll tax; if naturalized, and if so, date of papers and by what court issued; if transferred from another precinct, and if so, when and to what precinct.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Warren County (Va.). Circuit Court.
Subjects:
African Americans -- History -- 1877-1964.; African Americans -- Suffrage.; African Americans -- Virginia -- Warren County.; Suffrage -- Virginia -- Warren County.; Women -- Suffrage -- Virginia -- Warren County.
Geographical Names:
Warren County (Va.) -- Genealogy.; Warren County (Va.) -- History -- 19th century.; Warren County (Va.) -- History -- 20th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Election records -- Virginia -- Warren County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Warren County.; Voter's lists -- Virginia -- Warren County.
Contents List
- Commissions, Polls, Affidavits, Reports, 1836-1854
  Box 258 contains Commissions, Polls, Affidavits, Reports, 1836-1854.
- Commissions, Polls, Affidavits, Reports, 1861-1897
  Box 259 contains Commissions, Polls, Affidavits, Reports, 1861-1897.
- Commissions, Polls, Affidavits, Reports, 1861-1941
  Box 260 Commissions, Polls, Affidavits, Reports, 1861-1941.
- Permanent Rolls of Voters, 1902-1903
  This volume contains rolls of registered voters.
- Voter Registration Book, Colored, 1905-1908
  This volume contains lists of registered voters.
- List of Colored Voters, Bentonville Precinct, South River Magisterial District, 1902-1948
  Barcode Numbers 1096612-1096613, 1096616, and 1096622 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096638 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1919. Barcode Number 1096639 contains Voters Lists for 1919-1948.
- List of Colored Voters, Browntown Precinct, South River Magisterial District, 1902-1935 (bulk 1907-1935)
  Barcode Numbers 1096604, 1096611, 1096614, and 1096631 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Numbers 1096641 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1935.
- List of Colored Voters, Cedarville Precinct, Cedarville Magisterial District, 1902-1953
  Barcode Numbers 1096615 and 1096619 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096640 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1953.
- List of Colored Voters, Front Royal Precinct, Front Royal Magisterial District, 1901-1946
  Barcode Number 1096644 contains Voters Lists for 1901-1902 circa. Barcode Numbers 1096607 and 1096618 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096603 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1936. Barcode Number 1096589 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1946. Barcode Number 1096587 contains Voters Lists and Loose Papers for 1911-1920 circa.
- List of Colored Voters, Keller's School House Precinct, Cedarville Magisterial District, 1896-1902 circa
  Barcode Number 1096643 contains Voters Lists for 1896-1902 circa. Barcode Numbers 1096588, 1096621, and 1096632 contain Voters Lists for 1902.
- List of Colored Voters, Linden Precinct, Front Royal Magisterial District, 1902
  This volume contains Voter Lists for 1902.
- List of Colored Voters, Milldale Precinct, Cedarville Magisterial District, 1892-1947 (bulk 1902-1947)
  Barcode Number 1096642 contains Voters Lists for 1892-1899 circa. Barcode Number 1096610 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096636 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1939. Barcode Number 1096634 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1947. Barcode Number 1096635 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1931.
- List of Colored Voters, North Front Royal Precinct, Front Royal Magisterial District, 1902-1952
  This volume contains Voters List for 1902-1952.
- List of Colored Voters, Riverton Precinct, Fork Magisterial District, 1902-1940 (bulk 1935-1940)
  Barcode Number 1096606 contains a Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096608 contains Voters Lists for 1935-1940.
- List of Colored Voters, Rockland Precinct, Cedarville Magisterial District, 1902-1931.
  This volume contains Voters Lists of voters for 1902-1931.
- List of Colored Voters, South Precinct, Front Royal Magisterial District, 1915-1952
  This volume contains Voters Lists for 1915-1952.
- List of White Voters, Bentonville Precinct, 1902-1952
  Barcode Numbers 1096675 and 1096679 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096663 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Number 1096662 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1915. Barcode Numbers 1096667 and 1096671 contain Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096660 contains Voters Lists for 1904-1925. Barcode Number 1096661 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1952.
- List of White Voters, Bowman Precinct, 1902-1952
  Barcode Number 1096666 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096699 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Number 1096697 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1919. Barcode Number 1096670 contains Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096698 contains Voters Lists for 1911-1952.
- List of White Voters, Browntown Precinct, 1889-1952
  Barcode Number 1096696 contains Voters Lists for 1889-1926. Barcode Number 1096694 contains Voters Lists for 1892-1919. Barcode Number 1096700 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096695 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Numbers 1096711 and 1096712 contains Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096704 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1952.
- List of White Voters, Cedarville Precinct, 1902-1952
  Barcode Number 1096684 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096691 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Number 1096717 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1907. Barcode Numbers 1096714 contain Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096702 contains Voters Lists for 1905-1925. Barcode Number 1096715 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1952.
- List of White Voters, Fork Union Precinct, 1902-1925
  Barcode Number 1096678 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Numbers 1096669 and 1096713 contain Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode 1096650 contains Voters Lists for 1905-1925.
- List of White Voters, Fork Union Precinct, Fork Magisterial District, 1902-1952 (bulk 1906-1952)
  Barcode Number 1096609 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Number 1096630 contains Voters Lists for 1906-1952.
- List of White Voters, Front Royal Precinct, 1902-1950
  Barcode Number 1096649 contains Voters Lists undated, but possibly for 1899-1900. Barcode Numbers 1096707-1906710 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096692 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1904. Barcode Number 1096655 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1922. Barcode Number 1096647 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1925. Barcode Number 1096693 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1939. Barcode Number 1096646 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1950. Barcode Number 1096703 contains Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096683 contains Voters Lists for 1906-1922. Barcode Number 1096701 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1936. Barcode Numbers 1096648, 1096674, 1096682, 1096685 are undated Voters Lists.
- List of White Voters, Front Royal Precinct, Front Royal Magisterial District, 1902-1911
  This volume contains Voters Lists for 1902-1911.
- List of White Voters, Front Royal, North Precinct, 1906-1952
  Barcode Number 1096687 contains Voters Lists for 1906-1950. Barcode Number 1096686 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1952.
- List of White Voters, Front Royal, South Precinct, 1902-1952
  Barcode Number 109716 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1904, 1946. Barcode Number 1096705 contains Voters Lists for 1904-1952. Barcode Number 1096665 contains Voters Lists for 1905-1952.
- List of White Voters, Keller's School House Precinct, 1896-1952 (bulk 1902-1952)
  Barcode Number 1096657 contains Voters Lists for 1896-1900. Barcode Numbers 1096654 and 1096681 contain Voters Lists for 1902-1904. Barcode Number 1096653 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1946. Barcode Number 1096652 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1952.
- List of White Voters, Leary's School House Precinct, 1884-1893
  This volume contains Voters Lists for 1884-1893.
- List of White Voters, Linden Precinct, 1902-1952 (bulk 1907-1952)
  Barcode Numbers 1096673 and 1096706 contain Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096718 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Number 1096668 contains Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096720 contains Voters Lists for 1907-1952.
- List of White Voters, Milldale Precinct, 1902-1903
  Barcode Number 1096676 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096680 contains Voters Lists for 1903.
- List of White Voters, Milldale Precinct, Cedarville Magisterial District, 1902-1952
  Barcode Number 1096629 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1952. Barcode Number 1096628 contains Voters Lists for 1904-1952.
- List of White Voters, North Front Royal Precinct, Front Royal Magisterial District, 1902-1903
  This volume contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903.
- List of White Voters, Reliance Precinct, 1911-1952
  This volume contains Voters Lists for 1911-1952.
- List of White Voters, Riverton Precinct, 1902-1952
  Barcode Number 1096677 contains a Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096658 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1952. Barcode Number 1096719 contains Voters Lists for 1903. Barcode Number 1096659 contains Voters Lists for 1904-1952.
- List of White Voters, Rockland Precinct, 1902-1952.
  Barcode Number 1096689 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1940. Barcode Number 1096690 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1951. Barcode Number 1096688 contains Voters Lists for 1905-1952.
- List of White Voters, Waterlick Precinct, 1902-1903.
  Barcode Number 1096664 contains Voters Lists for 1902. Barcode Number 1096672 contains Voters Lists for 1903.
- List of White Voters, Waterlick Precinct, Fork Magisterial District, 1902-1952
  Barcode Number 1096626 contains Voters Lists for 1902-1903. Barcode Number 1096627 contains Voters Lists for 1904-1952.